# **Madhavi Patel**

Lansdale, PA 19446 • 267-421-9854 • Madhavip122@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/madhavip93 • https://madhavip93.github.io/

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Energetic and creative marketing candidate focused on positively impacting business goals and improving customer relations. A team player with top-notch communication skills, strong ability to solve problems, experience in social media, and a desire to continually learn and advance my abilities and skills within the field of Digital Marketing and CRM.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Science in Marketing**

Concentration in New Media and Communications Southern New Hampshire University December 2020

### **Bachelor of Science**

Elementary Education Pre K-4th Penn State University December 2016 Graduated with Honors

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Google Analytics

Graduated with Honors

- Content Marketing
- Google Ads Certified
- Microsoft Office Suite
- CRM (NetSuite & Salesforce)
- LinkedIn Sales Navigator

- Wordpress
- Pardot
- Graphic Design
- Canva
- Wix, Mail Chimp, Hootsuite

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Marketing Coordinator**

excelerateds2p

January 2023 - Current

- Created SAP/es2p full marketing plans for events and webinars across the United States. This included scheduling email blasts, social media posts, and outreach via LinkedIn Sales Navigator.
- Composed newsletters, articles on SAP business solutions, and event invites. Sent to 1000+ contacts through Pardot.
- Created registration pages in Wordpress for webinars and in-person events for users to indicate interest in attending events.
- Designed banners and digital invites with Canva for in-person conferences.
- Researched and coordinated with various transportation, food, swag, and hotel vendors to plan in-person events.
- Worked with internal consultants to develop a plan for marketing campaigns which included writing case studies and blog articles to promote effectiveness of SAP products.

## **CRM Data/Marketing Specialist**

April 2021 - January 2023

**Veterinarian Recommended Solutions** 

- Designed hundreds of email and physical mailing campaigns to drive attendance to in-person and online conferences, sent to 1000's of contacts with a 70% open rate.
- Researched and coordinated remote events such as "Wine Tasting", "Ice Cream Making", and "Paint & Sip".
   Ensured items were delivered to each participant and collected data on participation. Resulted in significant conversions to sales.
- Developed and posted daily social media posts for Facebook and LinkedIn.
- Analyzed results of conferences to spot trends or assess the response to different products, presented to the Leadership Team.
- Improved the quality of the database by cleaning customer contacts in Netsuite, helping Sales and Marketing teams better target potential clients.

Digital Marketing Intern

June 2020 - August 2020

**Onpoint Success** 

• Constructed social media content and email campaigns through Hootsuite/Mailchimp. Sent to 400 users/day with an average open rate of 55%.

• Created custom social media posts featuring testimonials, viral content, blogs, and informational graphics.

### **Digital Marketing Intern**

June 2019 - August 2019

Holiday Inn Express & Suites

- Responded to reviews on social media and third party websites to promote brand loyalty and collect insightful ideas to satisfy customers.
- Analyzed click through rate for booking website and tested improvements to increase number of bookings; led quarterly presentations to share results.

## **Public Relations, Marketing, and Communications Intern**

June 2018 - August 2018

The Gabriel Institute

- Researched marketing software solutions and presented results to the leadership team.
- Created the company's first press kit and added it as a new page on the company's website through Wix.
- Developed and posted daily tweets and Facebook posts to Company's social media platforms.
- Created blog content through Wordpress to increase SEO and inform customers about the company.

### **Instructional ParaProfessional**

September 2017 - April 2021

Skippack Elementary

- Analyzed student academic progress and created reports with graphics, work samples, and reports for administrators on a weekly basis.
- Utilized data from standardized exams to guide instruction and intervention.
- Utilized software such PowerPoint, Flipboard, and iMovie to create lessons that are visually appealing and provide necessary information in a memorable way.